Finding Aid for Women's Athletics (University of Michigan) records, 1972-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Title IX 1972-1986
  Other significant files in the Title IX series include: the Athletic Department compliance reports; the files on the three complaints filed against the Athletic Department which resulted in internal or HEW investigations; HEW Hearings and Regulations, which include reprints of the Title IX legislation and HEW enforcement regulations; newspaper clippings; and a number of articles and reports on Title IX and women's athletics. Also included here are minutes of the Ann Arbor Schools Title IX Monitoring Committee of which Phyllis Ocker was a member.
  - Chronology of Implementation 1979 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence and Reports
    - 1973 (Box 6)
    - 1975 (Box 6)
    - 1976 (Box 6)
    - 1976 (Engstrand Memos) (Box 6)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 6)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
    - 1982 (Box 6)
    - 1983-1986 (Box 6)
  - Compliance Reports 1976, 1978 (Box 6)
  - AIAW Materials
    - Correspondence 1976-1979 (Box 6)
    - Survey of Women's Athletics at AIAW Schools 1974 (Box 6)
  - Big Ten
    - Compliance Workshop Materials 1985 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and Reports 1974-1980 (Box 6)
    - Council of 10, Memos Reports etc. 1979-1979 (Box 6)
    - Complaints Filed
      - Federbush Complaint 1973-1977 (Box 6)
      - Golf Complaint (Beckett) 1976 (Box 6)
      - Track Complaint (Mayberry and Supler) 1979, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - HEW
    - Hearings and Regulations
      - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - Intercollegiate Athletics Investigators Manual 1980 (Box 7)
    - Compliance Reports of Other Schools 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - MAHPER (Michigan Association of Health, Physical Education, and Recreation), Correspondence, Minutes etc. 1977-1978 (Box 7)
  - Project on the Status and Education of Women of the Association of American Colleges, Reports etc. 1972-1975 (Box 7)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings 1972-1985, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - University of Texas Report, 19774 (Box 7)
  - Survey of Women's Athletic Programs (Big 10 and Mid-American Conferences) 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Publications and Reports, 2 folders
    - Bibliography and Investigation Guide 1977 (ACLU) (Box 7)
    - "Complying with Title IX," (AAHPER) circa 1974 (Box 7)
    - "Athletes and Equality: Solutions to the Title IX Controversy" by George R. La Noure (Box 7)
    - "Title IX: The Half Full, Half Empty Glass" 1981 (Box 7)
      (National Advisory Council on Women's Educational Programs)
    - "The Structure of Athletic Obstacles to Women's Involvement in Coaching" (Annelies Knopper et. al.) (Box 7)
    - "Brief Historical Summary of the Integration of Women into the Big Ten Conference Governance From 1974-1987" (Alyce Taylor Cheska) (Box 7)
    - "Women in Sports," 1978 (A Women's Equity Action League kit, includes extensive bibliography) (Box 7)
    - "Women in Intercollegiate Sport: A Longitudinal Study, Eleven year update" 1978 (R. Vivian Acosta, Linda Jean Carter) (Box 7)
    - "Studies of Intercollegiate Athletics, No. 1: Summary Results from the 1987/88 National Study of Intercollegiate Athletics" (Center for the Study of Athletics) (Box 7)
    - "Studies of Intercollegiate Athletics, No. 4: Women in Intercollegiate Athletics At NCAA Division I Institutions," 1989 (Center for the Study of Athletics) (Box 7)
  - Student Papers 1974-1978, 4 items (Box 7)
  - Ann Arbor Schools Title IX Monitoring Committee
    - Minutes, reports, etc
      - January 1983-May 1986 (Box 7)
      - September 8, 1986
        - September 15, 1986-November 23, 1988 (Box 7)
- Phyliss Ocker
  The small Phyllis Ocker series includes biographical material and notes for speeches.
  - Biographical Material (Box 7)
  - Notes for speeches circa 1976-1990, 2 folders (Box 7)
- Photographs
  Photographs include an aerial shot of Palmer Field a drawing of the proposed Women's Athletic building, Phyllis Ocker portraits, and several women's team photos.
  - Aerial of Palmer Field, Observatory, Hospital and Drawing of proposed Women's Athletic building 1987 (Box 7)
  - Women's Athletic Directors-Hartwig, Hunt, Ocker, Bradley-Doppes (Box 7)
  - Team Photos
    - Tennis 1975 (Box 7)
    - Synchronized swimming 1974/75 (Box 7)
    - Volleyball 1975/76 (Box 7)
  - Awards Lunch 1982 (contact sheet) (Box 7)